Guide to the Andrew Forest Muir papers MS 017
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Andrew Forest Muir papers
ca. 1916-1969
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Muir, Andrew Forest, 1916-1969
MS 017
41 Linear Feet 82 boxes
This material includes correspondence, research and genealogical notes which reflect the interests of historian and Rice University professor Andrew Forest Muir. They relate to 19th century Texas and Houston history; free African Americans in Texas pre-Civil War; the life and death of William Marsh Rice; the growth of the Catholic, Anglican, and Episcopal Churches in the 19th century via missionary work in Texas and Hawaii; and Hawaiian history, specifically clergymen in Hawaii. These research files were created and maintained by Andrew Forest Muir circa 1935-1969, with subjects covering a wide range of dates, circa 1750-1969, bulk 1800s, particularly the republic of Texas era and Civil War era. Other topics include Muir's academic career and personal life.
Biographical Sketch
Andrew Forest Muir was born January 8, 1916 in Houston Heights, Texas. He earned a Bachelor of Arts degree (1938) and a Master of Arts (1942) from Rice Institute, as well as a Ph.D. from the University of Texas (1949). While in Austin he taught at St. Luke's School and tutored English at the University of Texas (1942-44), also serving as acting director of the San Jacinto Museum of History (1943-44). Muir next traveled to Hawaii where, from 1945 to 1949, he worked as a civilian employee for the U.S. Engineers in Honolulu, Hawaii, taught history at the Iolany School, and later was Educational Advisor to the Commanding General at Schofield Barracks, Hawaii. He served as an Assistant Professor of History at Daniel Baker College in Brownwood, Texas, from 1951-53, before moving on to teach at the Polytechnic Institute, in San German, Puerto Rico for the 1953-54 academic year. Honored as a John Simon Guggenheim Memorial fellow for 1957-58, he then joined the history department at Rice Institute in 1958.
As a historian, Muir published numerous studies on religion and church leaders in Hawaii during the late eighteenth and nineteenth centuries, as well as several studies on free blacks in the Houston area. He also authored "Early Missionaries in Texas" (1941), "Railroad Enterprise in Texas, 1936-1841" (1944), "The Thirty-Second Parallel Pacific Railroad in Texas 1872" (1949), and "Thomas Jefferson Ewing, Texas Ward: Politician" (1952) as well as Texas in 1837, which he edited in 1958.
Known as an authority on William Marsh Rice, his work "William Marsh Rice and His Institute: A Biographical Study," was edited by Sylvia Stallings Morris and posthumously published in 1972. In addition, Muir contributed to "The Handbook of Texas," "Southwestern Historical Quarterly," the "Historical Magazine of the Protestant Episcopal Church," and the "Tennessee Historical Quarterly," and served as associate editor of the "Journal of Southern History."
Andrew Forest Muir died on February 3, 1969.
Scope and Contents
Correspondence, research and genealogical notes compiled by former Rice professor Andrew Forest Muir. Subjects include early Texas history, early Texans, particularly Houston and Harris county, and the Episcopal Church in Texas, as well as the Anglican Church in Hawaii. Muir made the notes as a student at Rice Institute and at the University of Texas. The largest group of materials is Muir's alphabetical subject research files which relate to 19th century Texas and Houston history; the life and death of William Marsh Rice; the growth of the Catholic, Anglican, and Episcopal Churches in the 19th century via missionary work in Texas and Hawaii; and Hawaiian history, specifically clergymen in Hawaii. These research files were created and maintained by Andrew Forest Muir circa 1935-1969, with subjects covering a wide range dates, circa 1750-1969, bulk 1800s.
Correspondents include fellow Texas historians, librarians and publishers such as Frank Wardlaw, Alfred A. Knopf, A.C. Greene, Angus Cameron (Editor, Alfred A. Knopf), attorney Cooper Ragan, William H. Masterson (regarding Journal of Southern History), Diana and Bill Hobby, J.W. Petty Jr. (Book Mart, Victoria, TX)
Also of interest is Muir's collection of original treasury notes and manuscripts (Series VI) which dates mainly from the Republic of Texas Era and the U.S. Civil War era, reflecting everyday life through local (county, city, state, Confederate) currency from Texas and Southern states, as well as correspondence, receipts, military orders, and more.
Access Restrictions
This material is open for research.
Stored onsite at the Woodson Research Center.
Acquisition Information
Gift of the estate of Andrew Forest Muir and through Ellis Rudy, 1973 and 2004.
Arrangement
Missing Title
Series I: Personal and family, 1872-1969 (Boxes 1-7)
Series II: Muir student records, 1933-1944 (Boxes 8-9)
Series III: Rice Institute papers, 1957-1968 (Boxes 10-14
Series IV: General correspondence, 1931-1969 (Boxes 14-23)
Series V: Alphabetical subject research files (Boxes 24-78)
Series VI: Original treasury notes and manuscripts, 1763-1908 (Boxes 79-80)
Series VII: Microfilm, 1800s (Box 82)
Series VIII: Diaries and ledgers, 1911-1950
Index Terms
Subjects
American Civil War (United States: 1861-1865); Slavery; Free African Americans; Money -- Confederate States of America; Nineteenth century; Marriage; Religion; Banks and banking; African Americans
Document Types
money; corrrespondence; clippings (information artifacts); scrapbooks; photographs; notes; typescripts
Places
Hawaii; Texas -- Matagorda; Texas -- Jefferson County; Texas -- Houston; United States; Texas -- Brazoria County; Texas; Texas -- Harris County; Texas -- Galveston; Texas -- Fort Bend County; Texas -- Burleson County
Subjects (Persons)
Houston, Sam, 1793-1863; Hammeken, George Louis, 1811-1881; Rice, William Marsh, 1816-1900; Muir, Andrew Forest, 1916-1969; Austin, Stephen F. (Stephen Fuller), 1793-1836; Autry, James Lockhart, 1830-1862; Gray, Peter William, 1787-1841; Muir family
Subjects (Corporations)
Rice University. Department of History.; Anglican Church in North America.; Episcopal Church. Diocese of Texas.; Catholic Church.; Christ Church Cathedral (Houston, Tex.).
- Series I: Personal and family, 1872-1969, 253214
  General note
  Dates appearing after a person's name relate to that person's birth and death dates, not to the actual contents of the file.
  - Genealogical correspondence, 1934-1950, 253351 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Genealogical research, British vital statistics, 253350 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Alberts, Hattie Merdora (McNew), 1893-, 253349 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Bailey, Alfonzo Miles, 1894-1918, 253348 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Bailey, Alfred Benjamin, 1853-1931, 253347 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Bailey, Alfred James, 1888-1956, 253346 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Bailey, Eleanor Jane, 1866, 253345 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Bailey, Isabella (Royal), 1854-1931, 253344 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Bailey, James, 1773/74 - 1852, 253343 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Bailey, Jane (Miles), 1830-1866, 253342 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Bailey, John, 1822/23-1866, 253341 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Bailey, John James, 1851-1919, 253340 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Bettridge, Effie Hannah (Bailey), 1896-, 253339 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Bettridge, Effie May, 1918-, 253338 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Bettridge, James, 1925-, 253337 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Bettridge, Joseph Orton, 1895-, 253336 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Bettridge, Paul, 1945, 253335 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Bingle, Georgia Hannay, 253334 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Blanke, Charles David, 1912-, 253333 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Blanke, Charles Thomas, 1935-, 253332 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Blanke, Fannie May (Melton), 1913-, 253331 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Bond, Ella Bertha (Meineke) Kittman, 1880-1940, 253330 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Brown, George James Ewing, 1922-, 253329 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Brown, James Steven, 1895-, 253328 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Brown, John Samuel Aaron, 1925-, 253327 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Brown, Myrtle May (Charwane), 1893-, 253326 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Buckingham, Beatrice (Bailey), d.1960, 253325 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Carrick, Nolie Anita (McNew) Ayrand, 1907-, 253324 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Cash, Bernice Mary Elaine (Brown), 1923-, 253323 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Cash, Raymond J., 1919-, 253322 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Charwane, Fannie Emily, 1895-1903, 253321 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Charwane, Martin Joseph, 1839-1916, 253320 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Charwane, Mary Hayes (Ewing) James, 1857-1932, 253319 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Clegg, Jake Barnes, 1892-1958, 253318 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Crenshaw, Frances Eliza (Meriwether), 1812-1898, 253317 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Ewing, Thomas Jefferson, 1810/11-1870, 253316 (Box 1, Folder 36-37)
  - Ewing, Thomas Jefferson, III, 1878-1942, 253315 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Foster, James W., 1824/25, 253314 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Goodbee, Cynthia Annie (Ewing), 1848-1868, 253313 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Goodbee, Frank, 1837-1878, 253312 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Gray, Samuel C., 253311 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Hallmark, Elizabeth E. (Love), 1832-1907, 253310 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Hallmark, Jefferson Davis, 253309 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Hallmark, Joseph Love, 1870-, 253308 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Huff, William P., 1811-1886, 253307 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - James, George Henry, 1881-1958, 253306 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - James, George Henry Hermann, 1881-1958, 253305 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - James, Thomas Jefferson, 1885-1954, 253304 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - James, William, 1830-1888, 253303 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - James, William Ewing, 1880-1926, 253302 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Jones, David Howell, 253301 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Jones, Jane (Williams) James, 1808/09-1868, 253300 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Jones, Margaret (James), 1833-1911, 253299 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Jones, Richard S., 1861-, 253298 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Jones, William R., 1859-1889, 253297 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Kittman, Arnold (1918-1919), 253296 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Kittman, William Plaze (1870-1918), 253295 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Love, Allen (-1853), 253294 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - McNew, Arthur John (1923-), 253293 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - McNew, Clarence Adolf (1925-1927), 253292 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - McNew, Dorsey Mason (1903-), 253291 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - McNew, George Hermann (1895-), 253290 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - McNew, Hugh (1838/39 - 1868), 253289 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - McNew, John Ewing (1896-), 253288 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - McNew, John Hugh (1868-1942), 253287 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - McNew, Thelma Elizabeth (1905-1918), 253286 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Meineke, Henrietta Merdora (Ewing) McNew (1850-1915), 253285 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Meineke, Loretta (Albrecht) (1888-1937), 253284 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Meineke, Theodore (1850-1936), 253283 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Meineke, Robert Price (1916-), 253282 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Meineke, William Henry Anton Thomas, 253281 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Melton, Henry Clay (-1930), 253280 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Meriwether family of Lowdnes County, Alabama, 253279 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Meriwether, David (1755-1822), 253278 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Meriwether, James S. (1814/15 -), 253277 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Meriwether, Jeremiah W. Doctor (1821-1851), 253276 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Meriwether, John Garland (1784?-1836), 253275 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Meriwether, Mary (Hays), 253274 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Meriwether, Samuel W. (1809/10), 253273 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Miles, Jane (1745/46-1818), 253272 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Miles, Joseph (1794/95-1861), 253271 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Miles, Mary (Willis) (-1862), 253270 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Miles, Reuben (1831-), 253269 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Miles, Robert, 253268 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Mosbruker, Ellouise (Meineke), 253267 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Muir family, transcribed letters, 1901-1938, 253266 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Muir, Andrew Forest, photographs, 1916-1969, 253265 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Muir, Andrew Forest, Daniel Baker College, Brownwood, TX, 1950-1964, 253264 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Muir house and family (real estate records), 253263 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Muir, Annie Jane (James) (1878-1927), 253262 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Muir, Annie Margarete (1912-1917), 253261 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Muir, Carol Ruth (1947), 253260 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Muir, Cynthia Anne (1939-), 253259 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Muir, James Thomas (1948-), 253258 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Muir, James Bailey (brother of AFM) (1914-1941), 253257 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Muir, Joseph William (Bailey) (1863-1929), 253256 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Muir, Joseph William (Bailey) infant daughter of (1908), 253255 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Muir, Joseph William (Bailey) infant son of (1919), 253254 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Muir, Juanita Jean (Ohlman) (1911-), 253253 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Muir, Lawrence Windham Bailey (1921-), 253252 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Muir, Letsy Jane (1945-), 253251 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Muir, Marion George Bailey (1906-1958), 253250 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Muir, Marion George III (1942), 253249 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Muir, Mattie Ruth (Hill) (1910-), 253248 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Muir, Samuel Ewing Bailey (1910-), 253247 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Muir, Sophia Elizabeth (Druitt) (1857-1943), 253246 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Muir, William (1845-1938) - transcriptions and notes, 253245 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Muir, William (1845-1938) - mss letters dated 1894-1936, 253244 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Muir, William Joseph Bailey (1904-), 253243 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Muir and related families - newsclippings (obituaries, etc.), 253242 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Scanlan, Flora May (Smith), 253241 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Smith, Addison Whittaker (1867-1925), 253240 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Smith, Addison Whittaker, infant son of (1894), 253239 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Smith, Addison Whittaker II (1900-1914), 253238 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Thomas, Ann (James), 253237 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Vetter, Jennie (Bailey) (1876-1948), 253236 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Wedeking, Annie Mary (Meineke) Walter Samperi (1878-), 253235 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Wells, Henrietta Merdona (Charwane) Melton Fitzpatrick (1892-1930), 253234 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Wells, Moritz Madison (1885-1931), 253233 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Wells, Sarah (Ivy) Light James, 253232 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Genealogical research notecards (alphabetically arranged notecards with names, birth & death dates), 253231 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Letter register, 253230 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Gifts to libraries and museums (AFM correspondence regarding), 253229 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Muir family scrapbooks, 253224
    - Scrapbook featuring ship on front, dated 1860-1934. Includes photographs, correspondence, calling cards, school report cards, event programs, and other ephemera, some belonging to Andrew Forest Muir and some to his ancestors., 253228 (Box 5, Folder -)
    - Scrapbook featuring horse and rider on front, dated 1877-1932. Includes family tax records, photographs, social invitations, church events, baptism records, birth certificates, some belonging to Andrew Forest Muir and some to his ancestors., 253227 (Box 5, Folder -)
    - Scrapbook dated 1872-1934. Includes family obituaries, newsclippings, correspondence related to AFM's parents., 253226 (Box 6, Folder -)
    - Panoramic views (2) of members of Order of de Molay, 1928 & 1931, 253225 (Box 6, Folder -)
  - Photographs: Friends, A-F, 1930s-1960s, 253223 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Photographs: Friends, G-Z, 1930s-1960s, 253222 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Photographs: unidentified persons, 253221 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Photographs: places, 253220 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Personal correspondence, 1958-1967, 253219 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Journal, 1950s, 253218 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Appointment books, 1958-59, 253217 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Appointment books, 1960-63, 253216 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Appointment books, 1964-65, 253215 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Series II: Muir student records, 1933-1944, 253199
  - Rice Institute, 1933-37, 253206
    - Diary / appointments, 1933-34, 253213 (Box 8, Folder -)
    - Diary / appointments, 1935, 253212 (Box 8, Folder -)
    - Diary / appointments, 1936, 253211 (Box 8, Folder -)
    - Reading list, 253210 (Box 8, Folder -)
    - Scrapbook, 1934-1937. Includes report cards, athletic game tickets, photographs from published materials, and other ephemera such as a green bow tie worn on Fridays while a freshman at Rice., 253209 (Box 9, Folder -)
    - Transcripts and ephemera, 253208 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Diplomas for bachelors and masters degrees, 253207 (Box Dr 33, Folder -)
  - University of Texas at Austin, 1944 and n.d., 253200
    - Class notes, 1944, 253205 (Box 9, Folder 2-3)
    - Class notes, Geology, n.d., 253204 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Research notes, n.d., 253203 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Transcripts, 253202 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Dipolma for Ph.D., 1949, 253201 (Box Dr 33, Folder -)
- Series III: Rice Institute papers, 1957-1968, 253084
  Scope and Contents note
  Includes lists of research topics and publications, administrative correspondence regarding salary and grant funding.
  - Guggenheim Fellowship at Rice to study William Marsh Rice, 1957-1958, 253198 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Lectureship at Rice Institute, 253192
    - 1958, 253197 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - 1959, 253196 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - 1960, 253195 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - 1961, 253194 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - 1962, includes promotion to Associate Professor, 253193 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Associate Professorship, 253188
    - 1963, 253191 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - 1964, 253190 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - 1965, includes promotion to Professor, 253189 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Professorship, 253184
    - 1966, 253187 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - 1967, 253186 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - 1968, 253185 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Departmental papers, 253173
    - 1959, 253183 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - 1960, 253182 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - 1961, 253181 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - 1962, 253180 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - 1963, 253179 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - 1964, 253178 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - 1965, 253177 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - 1966, 253176 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - 1967, 253175 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - 1968, 253174 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Instructional materials, 253140
    - History 110, Fall 1958, 253172 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - History 110, Spring 1959, 253171 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - History 110, Fall 1959, 253170 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - History 390, Fall 1959, 253169 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - History 110, Spring 1960, 253168 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - History 390, Spring 1960, 253167 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - History 110, Fall 1960, 253166 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - History 110, Spring 1961, 253165 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - History 110, Spring 1961, 253164 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - History 110, Fall 1961, 253163 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - History 110, Spring 1962, 253162 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - History 404, Spring 1962, 253161 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - History 110, Fall 1962, 253160 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - History 404, Fall 1962, 253159 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - History 110, Spring 1963, 253158 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - History 404, Spring 1963, 253157 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - History 110, Fall 1963, 253156 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - History 110, Spring 1964, 253155 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - History 390b, Spring 1964, 253154 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - History 110, Spring 1965, 253153 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - History 590b, Spring 1965, 253152 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - History 110, Fall 1965, 253151 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - History 110, Spring 1966, 253150 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - History 390b, Spring 1966, 253149 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - History 535b, Spring 1966, 253148 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - History 110, Spring 1967, 253147 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - History 110, Fall 1966, 253146 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - History 390b / 590b, Spring 1967, 253145 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - History 390b / 590b, Spring 1967, 253144 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - History 110, Spring 1968, 253143 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - History 535b, Spring 1968, 253142 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - History 315, Fall 1968, 253141 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Graduate students - History, 253128
    - 1958, 253139 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - 1959, 253138 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - 1960, 253137 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - 1961, 253136 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - 1962, 253135 (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - 1963, 253134 (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - 1964, 253133 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - 1965, 253132 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - 1966, 253131 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - 1967, 253130 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - 1968, 253129 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Graduate Committee, 253123
    - 1963, 253127 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - 1965, 253126 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - 1966, 253125 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - 1967, 253124 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Fondren Library Committee, 253115
    - 1962, 253122 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - 1963, 253121 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - 1964, 253120 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - 1965, 253119 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - 1966, 253118 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - 1967, 253117 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - 1968, 253116 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - University Committee on Undergraduate Curriculum, 253110
    - 1965, 253114 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - 1966, 253113 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - 1967, 253112 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - 1968, 253111 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Journal of Southern History, 253103
    - 1958, 253109 (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - 1959, 253108 (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - 1960, 253107 (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - 1961, 253106 (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - 1962, 253105 (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - 1963, 253104 (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - College Lecture Series, 1959-60, 253102 (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - Proposed Urban Studies Center, Rice University, 1965-66, 253101 (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - Rice University Semicentennial Year, 1962-63, 253100 (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - Mary Hayes Ewing Publication Prize in Southern History, 1967, 253099 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Fondren Library, 253085
    - Edward Watson Kelley Collection, 1967, 253098 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Peden Memorial Collection, 1964, 253097 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Fondren Manuscript Collections, 1966-67, 253096 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Fondren Manuscript Collections: James Lockhart Autry papers, 1959-1963, 253095 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Fondren Manuscript Collections: James Lockhart Autry papers, 1959-1963, 253094 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Fondren Manuscript Collections: Don Carlos Buell papers, 1961-1962, 253093 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Fondren Manuscript Collections: Mary Pauline Dillingham papers, 1959, 253092 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Fondren Manuscript Collections: Hallie Rienzi (Johnston)Russell Thomas Flint papers, 1959, 253091 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Fondren Manuscript Collections: William Harrison Hamman papers, 1967, 253090 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Fondren Manuscript Collections: Masterson Family papers, 1957, 253089 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Fondren Manuscript Collections: Osterhout Family papers, 1957, 253088 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Accessions to Fondren Library, 253087 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Exhibits in Fondren Library, 253086 (Box 14, Folder 14)
- Series IV: General correspondence, 1931-1969, 253028
  - Postcards, 1941-1957, 253083 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - 1958, 253082 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - 1958, 253081 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - 1959, 253080 (Box 15, Folder 1-2)
  - 1960, 253079 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - 1961, 253078 (Box 16, Folder 1-5)
  - 1962, 253077 (Box 17, Folder 1-5)
  - 1963, 253076 (Box 18, Folder 1-5)
  - 1964, 253075 (Box 19, Folder 1-4)
  - 1965, 253074 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - 1965, 253073 (Box 20, Folder 1-3)
  - 1966, 253072 (Box 20, Folder 4-5)
  - 1966, 253071 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - 1967, 253070 (Box 21, Folder 2-4)
  - 1968-69, 253069 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - 1968-69, 253068 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Undated correspondence, 253067 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Alphabetical correspondence, 253029